# KATE ATTARDO

Brooklyn, NY | kateattardo@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **FULLSTACK DEVELOPER**

I'm a software engineer with extensive experience in small business ownership. I grew my business three hundred percent in three years. Implementing an app for my clients sparked my interest in programing, it blends my pragmatic and creative skill sets. I'm dedicated to creating a seamless user experience.

#### SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MERN-STACK infrastructure

Libraries and Frameworks: NodeJS, ExpressJS, EJS, Django, React, Bootstrap, Materialize

Databases and other: MongoDB, MongooseODM, PostgreSQL

Tools: Git, Postman, VS Code, AmazonS3, Flyio, Netlify, Firebase, Render, DOM Manipulation

**Interpersonal skills:** Team Collaboration, Communication, Time management

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Kitchwitch: <u>Frontend</u> | <u>Backend</u> | <u>App</u> | Two project architecture, MERN-Stack | React | Express

A recipe application where users input ingredients they have on hand and receive recipes.

- Engineered a RESTFUL backend to pull recipes from and API and created comment functionality for users to make notes.
- Created a compelling user interface with CSS and Bootstrap.
- · Implemented JSON bearer token to create and authenticate user credentials.

# TaskMaster - GitHub | App | Python | Django

An application for workflow productivity to assign projects and individual tasks to employees.

- Collaborated as a team of three remote engineers to build a task management app for users to increase productivity in the workplace.
- · Implemented Amazon S3 for users to upload photos for their profile.
- · Utilized Django ORM and PostgreSQL database for users to store projects and tasks assigned to them.

### Parklopedia- GitHub | App - JavaScript | Express | MongoDB

An application allowing users to rate local parks and park features.

- · Authorized users with Google OAuth to sign in and out of profiles.
- · Followed MVC architecture and RESTFUL routes with Express.
- · Utilized MongoDB allowing users to easily access selected parks, comments, and reviews.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Full-Stack Developer

10/2023 - Current.

Brooklyn, NY,

- · Consulting with three separate clients to assess development needs and style for brand Websites
- · Implementing client-focused approach to build rich, accessible, and user-friendly interfaces for small business and non-profit companies.

# Dog Walk Daily, Owner/Operator

Brooklyn, NY,

10/2016 - Current.

- · Owner/operator of a boutique dog care business serving one hundred twenty-five clients daily and overseeing a staff of fourteen.
- Oversee all daily operations including scheduling, billing, client/staff liaison, advertising.
- · Organize and host quarterly staff appreciation events.

# **Hudson Guild, Mental Health Counselor** 9/2014 - 09/2016

NY, NY,

- · Mental Health Counselor working with patients with PTSD, Anxiety, Grief, Body Dysmorphia, Substance Abuse, and Personality Disorders.
- Analyzed and conceptualized diagnoses for patients to implement treatment plans.
- · Conducted talk therapy sessions to reinforce coping skills and change behaviors.
- Collaborated with clinicians to address patient needs and present weekly cases.

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly Certificate Completed Fordham University Masters, Education School of Visual Arts Bachelors, Photography

Remote10/2023 NY, NY, Graduated: 5/2013

NY, NY, Graduated: 5/2005